A Guide to the Governor Wilson Cary Nicholas Executive Papers, 1814-1816
Library of Virginia
Other noteworthy items include: certificates of oath for Nicholas as governor (1814 Dec. 12 & 1815 Dec. 12); a proclamation directing that the court for Essex County be held in the building erected for the Clerk's Office in Tappahannock (1814 Dec. 17); an account of munitions of war on hand at the magazine at Westham, the Laboratory, & fixed ammunition in the Penitentiary (1814 Dec. 19 & 24); a resolution of the Louisiana General Assembly re. gratitude for the citizens of Louisiana during the invasion by the British (1815 Feb. 1); a proclamation of Governor Nicholas offering a reward for the apprehension of Armistead Atkins (1815 Feb. 2); a proclamation of Governor Nicholas offering a reward for the apprehension of John Oneale (1815 March 20); a proclamation of Governor Nicholas offering a reward for the apprehension of Littleberry Hurt (1815 March 20); proceedings of the Quarterly Meetings of the Board of Visitors of the Virginia Penitentiary (1815 April 14; 1815 June 8; 1815 July 1 & 29; 1815 Sept. 28); proceedings of the Visitors of the Penitentiary re. the causes of the fire (1815 April 16 & 1815 June 8); a proclamation of Governor Nicholas offering a reward for the apprehension of Thomas Douglas (1815 April 17); a proclamation of Lt. Gov. Linah Mims offering a reward for the apprehension of Robert Loggins (1815 May 17); the certificate of oath of William Carson as a member of the Privy Council (1815 June 21); proceedings of the Board of Visitors (1815 July 8 & 22; 1815 Oct. 12; 1816 Feb. 24); a proclamation of Governor Nicholas for an election to replace Matthew Clay, a representative in Congress (1815 July 29); a proclamation of Governor Nicholas offering a reward for the apprehension of Jonathan Piercy & Curtis McCleester (1815 Nov. 20 & 1816 May 22); a proclamation of Governor Nicholas offering a reward for the apprehension of Galloway Burke (1815 Nov. 20); a certificate of oath for John Tyler as a member of the Privy Council (1815 Dec. 9); a proclamation of Governor Nicholas offering a reward for the apprehension of Robert Gibson (1815 Dec. 14); proceedings of the Monthly Board of Visitors (1815 April 22 & June 24); the bond of John Burfoot as Auditor of Public Accounts (1816 Jan. 3); court records from Louisa & Spotsylvania counties re. the insurrection of George Boxley (1816 March 5); a proclamation of Governor Nicholas offering a reward for the apprehension of Levy Gibson (1816 May 4); proceedings of a meeting of the Nottoway Tribe of Indians for the purpose of choosing new trustees (1816 May 11); a proclamation of Governor Nicholas offering a reward for the apprehension of Thomas Richardson (1816 May 14); a proclamation of Governor Nicholas offering a reward for the apprehension of Elijah Davidson (1816 May 14); a proclamation of Governor Nicholas offering a reward for the apprehension of George Boxley (1816 May 18); a proclamation of Governor Nicholas for an election to fill the vacancy in Congress occasioned by the death of Thomas Gholson (1816 Aug. 30); the contract of Thomas Strode with the Commonwealth to execute Godefroy's plan for regulating the surface of the Public Square (1816 Sept. 30); a proclamation of Governor Nicholas offering a reward for the apprehension of Carrington Simpson (1816 Sept. 20); a proclamation of Governor Nicholas for an election to fill the vacancy in Congress occasioned by the death of John Clopton (1816 Sept. 24); a report of the commissioners appointed by the act of the Legislature of North Carolina to incorporate a company to cut a canal from Roanoke to Meherrin River & from the waters of the Chowan River to the James River or Dismal Swamp Canal (1816 Nov. [N.D.]); a certificate of election of electors for President & Vice President of the United States on behalf of Virginia (1816 Dec. 3); and a deed of covenant between Edward W. Trent & Orris Paine, Superintendent of the Improvement of the Public Square, to furnish granite stone for the support of the iron railing around the Square (1816 Dec. 10).
Arrangement
Arranged chronologically by date of document with pardons and undated items arranged to the rear.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Bibliography
Flournoy, H. W., CALENDAR OF VIRGINIA STATE PAPERS, January 1, 1808-December 31, 1835, VOL. X, Richmond: James E. Goode, Printer, 1892.
Contents List
- Wilson Cary Nicholas Executive Papers
- 1814
  - December
    - 12-20 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - 21-31 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Filing Jackets (Box 1, Folder 3)
- 1815
  - January
    - 1-10 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - 11-31 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Filing Jackets (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - February
    - 1-10 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - 11-19 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - 20-28 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Filing Jackets (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - March
    - 1-15 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - 18-31 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Filing Jackets (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - April
    - 1-15 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - 16-30 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Filing Jackets (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - May
    - 1-10 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - 11-20 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - 22-31 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Filing Jackets (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - June
    - 1-10 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - 11-20 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - 21-30 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Filing Jackets (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - July
    - 1-15 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - 16-31 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Filing Jackets (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - August
    - 3-15 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - 11-20 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Filing Jackets (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - September
    - 2-30 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Filing Jackets (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - October
    - 2-14 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - 17-31 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Filing Jackets (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - November
    - 2-19 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - 20-30 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Filing Jackets (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - December
    - 1-14 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - 17-29 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Filing Jackets (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Pardons (Box 3, Folder 13)
- 1816
  - January
    - 1-15 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - 16-31 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Filing Jackets (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - February
    - 1-15 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - 16-28 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Filing Jackets (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - March
    - 1-8 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - 9-20 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - 22-30 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Filing Jackets (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - April
    - 1-15 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - 16-30 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Filing Jackets (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - May
    - 1-15 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - 16-30 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Filing Jackets (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - June
    - 1-9 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - 10-20 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - 21-30 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Filing Jackets (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - July
    - 1-10 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - 11-19 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - 22-30 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Filing Jackets (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - August
    - 1-15 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - 16-30 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Filing Jackets (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - September
    - 2-20 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - 23-30 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Filing Jackets (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - October
    - 1-20 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - 21-30 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Filing Jackets (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - November
    - 1-29 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Filing Jackets (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - December
    - 1-10 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Filing Jackets (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Pardons (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Oversized (Clamshell Box)
  - 1814
    - Dec. [N.D] (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - 1815
    - Jan. [N.D.] (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Feb. [N.D.] (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - May 10 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - May [N.D.] (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - June 2 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - June 27 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - June [N.D.] (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - July 19 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - July [N.D.] (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Aug. 30 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Aug. [N.D.] (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Sept. 7 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Sept. 29 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Sept. [N.D.] (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Oct. 2 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Oct. [N.D.] (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Nov. 14 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Pardons
      - Archer (slave) (Box 7, Folder 19)
      - Caesar(slave) (Box 7, Folder 20)
      - Hollingshead, Richard (Box 7, Folder 21)
      - Pasley, Solomon (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - 1816
    - Jan. 3 (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - Jan. 3 (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - April 1 (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - May 11 (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - Sept. 9 (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - Sept. 30 (Box 16, Folder 28)
- Oversized (Newspaper Box)
  - 1815
    - Feb. 1 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - April [N.D.] (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - June 17 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Aug. 21 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Sept. 15 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Oct. 6 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Nov. 10 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - 1816
    - Jan. 17 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Feb. 4 (Box 8, Folder 9)